# Sondre Agledahl

Curriculum Vitae

Portfolio: sondreagledahl.com Email: sondre.agledahl.16@ucl.ac.uk Phone: (0)78 7376 1954

### Personal Summary

Games programmer with several published independent games, particularly experienced in Unity (2+ years), but possessing strong skills in low-level languages (C, C++ and assembly) as well. Currently pursuing a MEng Computer Science degree at University College London.

# Skills and abilities

- Highly proficient at programming gameplay mechanics and implementing level designs and assets in Unity and C#. Very familiar with all stages of the Unity development process from start to finish.
- Experienced C, C++ and assembly language programmer; highly competent at low-level memory management and optimisation.
- Have dedicated the past 3 years to developing my own independent games, one of which was voted the winner of a "Best of 2016" award at a game development website.

### Relevant work experience

### June 2017 Games programmer, Innotech LLC. (London, UK)

- Developed upon existing Unity-based match-three mobile puzzle game
- Single-handedly implemented many new features and game modes.
- Integrated new features with in-game-purchases.

Sept 2017-Present Computer Science lab mentor, University College London (London, UK)

• Tutoring first-year computer science students in programming (C, Haskell, Java) every week.

## June 2017-Present Microsoft Student Partner, Microsoft (London, UK)

- Lead organiser of PixelJam, Microsoft-sponsored game jam at UCL.
- Wrote article on Mixed Reality game development for the Microsoft Development Network.

# Education

### University College London (London, UK)

MEng Computer Science, September 2016 – present (Predicted 1st class)

- Game development director at UCL Tech Society: Organised and led PixelJam, university's first 24hour game jam, with sponsorships from Microsoft, Unity and Studio Gobo
- Developing iOS AR game for visually impaired players in collaboration project with Microsoft
- Created space shooter game controlled by accelerometer on Arduino microcontroller in C
- Developed multi-platform medical application through C# / Xamarin for client at UC Hospital

# Senja VGS (Finnsnes, Norway)

International Baccalaureate Diploma Programme, August 2014 – May 2016

- Received distinction for highest IB score ever awarded in Northern Norway (42)
- Founded and led programming tutoring group, teaching programming and game development through Python (with use of the PyGame framework)

### Extracurriculars and other distinctions

- As part of Aardvark Swift's Rising Star 2017 competition scored among the best internationally in C++ development test and passed to competition's second round.
- Received "Funniest Hack" award alongside my three teammates at the Porticode UCL hackathon in 2016 for creating JavaScript-based browser game